today we are gonna talk about privilege
and it is a concept I have looked into
him familiar with and I get it and I
don't think it's helping us and I think
this morning I tapped into why it's not
helping us and when I think of my areas
where I have privilege and when I think
of the areas where I don't have
privilege and I think of all those other
people who have privilege part of what I
want to do is obtain some of their
privilege it's like they're rich and I'm
poor I want to go up to like the white
sis able-bodied man and be like please
so can I just have a little bit of your
privilege just a little bit and they
can't because it's not transferable even
if they wanted to they can't transfer it
and so we're asking all of these people
to acknowledge their privilege when
there's nothing they can really do about
it and I think there's a better analogy
that actually puts us in power actually
gives us our own individual empowerment
and that isn't that we're walking around
with buckets of privilege that people
couldn't yet not transferable in any way
but instead we're every single person on
this planet is walking around with their
own container of trauma and they're full
up
so the Karan's of the world have their
little teacup of trauma
oh no can we meet the country club
requirements this book oh no that is
like it's laughable to me that might be
their trauma but it's theirs it's
central in their life and they're full
up of trauma they cannot take on anymore
whereas other people are walking around
with big huge buckets of trauma they
have poverty and intergenerational stuff
they have their they have racism and
sexism and ableism being thrown at them
constantly
they have big huge buckets of trauma
there's nowhere to pour their trauma
because everyone's full up and as they
look it's like spilling everywhere and
they got a bigger bucket so it's having
more of an impact
Caryn's are like I don't know why you're
such a mess my little teacup never
really makes a mess but the beautiful
part of this analogy so in this world we
don't know how to deal with their own
trauma even though there's nothing more
beneficial to your own life than healing
with your own trauma sitting with your
own shadow and healing it and loving it
is never gonna be like the payoff for
math there's nothing greater and yet we
still don't do it and yet what we're
asking it's someone we've labeled as
fragile to take on more they can't they
can't handle their own trauma let alone
your huge bucket of trauma but what I
can do as an individual no matter how
big or small my bucket is to acknowledge
I have a bucket of Charma heal it to
give myself any amount of capacity to
offer to take on somebody else's how can
I lighten your load
how can I help you but I can't demand
anyone else do that and take off my
trauma take on my drama they can't
they're not capable they're full up of
their own and the beautiful thing is
that people with the larger your trauma
bucket is and the more healing you do
the more capacity you have to heal this
world the Karan's of the world with
their tiny little little teacup of
trauma even if they fully healed which
is impossible even if they fully healed
they have a tiny little capacity for
your trauma and that's if they're fully
healed and so we've labeled especially
white Karan's as white fragility and yet
we're asking them to take on more how
can we label something as fragile and
ask it to bear more weight and not see
that that would absolutely crush it
because there is a truth than that
there's a truth that they're little
fragile teacup is full up and they can't
take on any more but we can we can heal
ourselves and we can offer the
resiliency to heal each other and when
we stop begging for privilege and just
start interweaving the resiliency and
antifragility we can create a world that
works for
absolutely everyone we're not begging
for privilege we're actually healing our
trauma all the trauma and all of the
spilling that comes out in the world in
all the ways a better world is on its
way please like and subscribe